Cope, Elmer F. Papers on Microfilm 5862 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Elmer F. Cope Papers on Microfilm
1903-1965
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Cope, Elmer Fern
5862 mf
6 cubic feet
55 microfilm reels
Papers (documents), microfilm.
This microfilm edition of the Elmer F. Cope Papers consists of correspondence (50% of collection), reports (20% of collection), newspaper clippings (20% of the collection), and other items (10% of the collection). The other items include bills, travel brochures, tickets, transportation schedules, greeting cards, business cards, appointment books, and calendars. The original papers are held by the Ohio Historical Society, Collection no.137.
5722532
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 12, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Elmer Fern Cope was born July 24, 1903 at Ellwood, Indiana. Besides his political leadership Cope worked in other areas to improve labor's image in the community, to increase and improve labor education, to strengthen the Department of Church and Economic Life of the National Council of Churches, and to complete the merger of AFL and CIO agencies in Ohio. In May, 1963, he announced his resignation of his Ohio AFL-CIO office for reasons of health.
Scope and Contents
The collection provides substantial information on Cope's working years, but contains scanty material on his early years. The Elmer F. Cope Papers contain information on Cope's childhood, schooling, and career. His high-school and college educational experiences (1919-1930) are documented in boxes 1 to 5.
The emphasis on his years (1929- 1930) at Brookwood Labor College and his association with A.J. Muste. Material covering period from 1929-1934, in boxes 6 to 11, contains correspondence and newspaper clippings on such labor-related subjects as the Empire Steel Corporation strike of 1931, Father James R. Cox's "Jobless March" in 1932, and the Steel Strike in Warren, Ohio of 1932.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: The Elmer Fern Cope Papers Ohio Historical Society Collection no 137
Cope, Elmer F. (Elmer Fern), 1903-1965
5722532
- Correspondence, 1929 (Reel 1)
  - Biographical compilations, 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Box 1: Folder 1.
  - Birth certificate, 1903; 2 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 2.
  - Warren, Ohio, High School, 1919-1923; 3 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 3.
  - Ohio Wesleyan University, 1924-1927; 4 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 4.
  - Swarthmore College; official record, 1927-1929; 5 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 5.
  - Swarthmore course: Political institutions of U.S. and England, 1927-1928; 6 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 6.
  - Swarthmore course: Origins of modern capitalism, 1927-1928; 7 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 7.
  - College students in industry: American Friends Service Committee, 1927-1929; 8 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 8.
  - Correspondence, 1927-1928; 9 (Reel 1)
    Box 1: Folder 9.
  - Swarthmore course: Development of economic thought., 1927-1928; 10 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 1. (or 1928-1929)
  - Swarthmore seminar: Economic problems. (1), 1927-1928; 11 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 2.
  - Swarthmore seminar: Economic problems. (2), 1928-1929; 12 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 3.
  - Swarthmore course: Democracies and dictatorships., 1928-1929; 13 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 4.
  - Swarthmore course: Social economics, 1928-1929; 14 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 5.
  - Correspondence, 1929; 15 (Reel 1)
    Box 2: Folder 6.
- Civil liberties, 1923-1932 to Wages + Prices 1928-1930 (Reel 2)
  - Clippings and leaflets, Civil liberties, 1923-1930; 1 (Reel 2)
    Box 2: Folder 7.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Government ownership., 1924-1930; 2 (Reel 2)
    Box 2: Folder 8.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Scientific management., 1925-1926; 3 (Reel 2)
    Box 2: Folder 9.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Labor youth., 1925-1930; 4 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 1.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Capitalism., 1925-1930; 5 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 2.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Cooperation of labor and management, 1925-1930; 6 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 3.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Race relations, 1926-1929; 7 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 4.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Business; Business conditions, 1926-1929; 8 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 5.
  - Clippings and leaflets, British labor, 1926-1931; 9 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 6.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Book reviews, 1926-1931; 10 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 7.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Coal, 1926-1932; 11 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 8.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Trade unionism, 1927-1929; 12 (Reel 2)
    Box 3: Folder 9.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Presidential politics, 1928; 13 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 1.
  - Clippings and leaflets, The A F of L - its southern campaign, 1928-1930; 14 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 2.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Automobile industry, 1928-1930; 15 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 3.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Wages and prices, 1928-1930; 16 (Reel 2)
    Box 4: Folder 4.
- 1928-1931, Courts, judges + police to Foreign relations Haiti 1929-1930 (Reel 3)
  - Clippings and leaflets, Courts, judges, and police, 1928-1931; 1 (Reel 3)
    Box 4: Folder 5.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Foreign relations - reparations, war debts, disarmament, 1928-1931; 2 (Reel 3)
    Box 4: Folder 6.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Russia, 1928-1932; 3 (Reel 3)
    Box 4: Folder 7.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Wealth - Distribution of, 1928-1932; 4 (Reel 3)
    Box 4: Folder 8.
  - Marion, N.Ca. textile mill troubles: literature and photographs, 1929; 5 (Reel 3)
    Box 4: Folder 9. July-December, 1929
  - Marion, N.Ca. textile mill troubles: correspondence, 1929; 6 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 1. July-December, 1929
  - Brookwood Labor College: courses of J.C. Kennedy, 1929-1930; 7 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 2.
  - Brookwood Labor College: A.J. Muste's course on Union constitutions, 1929-1930; 8 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 3.
  - Brookwood Labor College: A.J. Muste's other courses, 1929-1930; 9 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 4.
  - Brookwood Labor College: Saposs's course on American labor history, 1929-1930; 10 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 5.
  - Brookwood Labor College: Saposs's other courses, 1929-1930; 11 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 6.
  - Brookwood Labor College: courses by Budenz, Norton, Starr, Tippett, 1929-1930; 12 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 7.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Foreign relations - Haiti, 1929-1930; 13 (Reel 3)
    Box 5: Folder 8.
- 1929-1932, Needle trades to Social insurance (Reel 4)
  - Clippings and leaflets, Needle trades, 1929-1930; 1 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 1.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Textile industry-labor conditions, 1929-1930; 2 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 2.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Pennsylvania politics, 1929-1930; 3 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 3.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Labor's political action, 1929-1930; 4 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 4.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Public utilities, 1929-1930; 5 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 5.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Steel and iron - general, 1929-1930; 6 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 6.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Agriculture, 1929-1931; 7 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 7.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Intercollegiate, 1929-1931; 8 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 8.
  - Clippings and leaflets, The tariff, 1929-1931; 9 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 9.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Conference for Progressive Labor Action, 1929-1932; 10 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 10.
  - Clippings and leaflets, U.S. Steel Corporation, 1929-1932; 11 (Reel 4)
    Box 6: Folder 11.
  - Correspondence, 1930; 12 (Reel 4)
    Box 7: Folder 1.
  - Amalgamated Association of Iron, Steel and Tin Workers, 1930; 13 (Reel 4)
    Box 7: Folder 2.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Biographical, 1930; 14 (Reel 4)
    Box 7: Folder 3.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Prohibition, 1930; 15 (Reel 4)
    Box 7: Folder 4.
  - Clippings, leaflets, and notes, Social Insurance, 1930; 16 (Reel 4)
    Box 7: Folder 5.
- War costs 1930-1931 to Correspondence, May-Jul 1932 (Reel 5)
  - Clippings and leaflets, War costs, 1930-1931; 1 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 6.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Railroads and labor, 1930-1932; 2 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 7.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Steel: Bethlehem, Youngstown merger, 1930-1932; 3 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 8.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Ohio legislative proposals, 1930-1932; 4 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 9.
  - Clippings and leaflets, Socialist Party, 1931-1932; 5 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 10.
  - Correspondence, 1931; 6 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 11. January-April, 1931.
  - Correspondence, 1931; 7 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 12. May-September, 1931.
  - May Mansfield, O., Empire Steel Corporation strike, 1931; 8 (Reel 5)
    Box 7: Folder 13. May, 1931.
  - Correspondence, 1931; 9 (Reel 5)
    Box 8: Folder 1. October-December, 1931.
  - Federated Press copy, 1931; 10 (Reel 5)
    Box 8: Folder 2. October 1931 - February 1932.
  - Correspondence, 1932; 11 (Reel 5)
    Box 8: Folder 3. January-April, 1932.
  - Father Jas. R. Cox's "Jobless March" on Washington, 1932; 12 (Reel 5)
    Box 8: Folder 4. January, 1932.
  - Clippings, Father Cox's march, 1932; 13 (Reel 5)
    Box 8: Folder 5. January-October, 1932.
  - Correspondence, 1932; 14 (Reel 5)
    Box 8: Folder 6. May-July, 1932.
- Correspondence, Aug 1932 to Jun 1933 (Reel 6)
  - Correspondence, 1932; 1 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 1. August-October, 1932.
  - Warren, O., steel strike, 1932; 2 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 2. September, 1932.
  - Correspondence, 1932; 3 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 3. November-December 10, 1932.
  - Correspondence, 1932; 4 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 4. December 11-21, 1932.
  - Correspondence, 1933; 5 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 5. January, 1933.
  - Cooperative Distributors, Inc., 1933; 6 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 6. January, 1933.
  - Correspondence, 1933; 7 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 7. February, 1933.
  - Correspondence, 1933; 8 (Reel 6)
    Box 9: Folder 8. March, 1933.
  - Correspondence, 1933; 9 (Reel 6)
    Box 10: Folder 1. April, 1933.
  - Correspondence, 1933; 10 (Reel 6)
    Box 10: Folder 2. May, 1933.
  - Correspondence, 1933; 11 (Reel 6)
    Box 10: Folder 3. June, 1933.
- Correspondence, Jul 1933 to Western Reserve course Ed. 403 (Reel 7)
  - Correspondence, 1933; 1 (Reel 7)
    Box 10: Folder 4. July-September, 1933.
  - Correspondence, 1933; 2 (Reel 7)
    Box 10: Folder 5. October-December, 1933.
  - Correspondence, 1934; 3 (Reel 7)
    Box 10: Folder 6. January-February, 1934.
  - Notes and clippings, CWA reduction - Ohio, 1934; 4 (Reel 7)
    Box 10: Folder 7. January, 1934.
  - Correspondence, 1934; 5 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 1. March-April, 1934.
  - Correspondence, 1934; 6 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 2. May-July, 1934.
  - Correspondence, 1934; 7 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 3. August-December, 1934.
  - Items of uncertain date, 1931-1934; 8 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 4.
  - Clippings and leaflets, 1934; 9 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 5.
  - Correspondence, 1935; 10 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 6.
  - Western Reserve University: Official record, 1935-1936; 11 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 7.
  - Western Reserve course Ed. 403: Philosophy of education., 1935-1936; 12 (Reel 7)
    Box 11: Folder 8.
- Western Reserve courses Ed. 451 to Ed. 468, 1935-1936 (Reel 8)
  - Western Reserve Course, Ed. 451: Statistical methods and research, 1935-1936; 1 (Reel 8)
    Box 12: Folder 1.
  - Western Reserve Course, Ed. 452: Statistical methods and research, 1935-1936; 2 (Reel 8)
    Box 12: Folder 2.
  - Western Reserve Course, Ed. 451: papers to be marked, 1935-1936; 3 (Reel 8)
    Box 12: Folder 3.
  - Western Reserve Course, Ed. 352: Methods of teaching history, 1935-1936; 4 (Reel 8)
    Box 12: Folder 4.
  - Western Reserve Course, Geog. 452: Geographic factors in economic and social development, 1935-1936; 5 (Reel 8)
    Box 12: Folder 5.
  - Western Reserve Course, Ed. 468: Practice teaching, 1935-1936; 6 (Reel 8)
    Box 12: Folder 6.
- Western Reserve course, Ed. 456, 1935-1936 to Steelworkers papers, 1943 (Reel 9)
  - Western Reserve Course, Ed. 456: unit on Teachers Unions, 1935-1936; 1 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 1.
  - Western Reserve University: Master of Arts examination, 1935-1936; 2 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 2.
  - Clippings, 1935-1936; 3 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 3.
  - Correspondence, 1936; 4 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 4.
  - Correspondence, 1937; 5 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 5.
  - Education, 1937-1938; 6 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 6. July 1937-January 1938.
  - Correspondence, 1938; 7 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 7.
  - Correspondence, 1939; 8 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 8.
  - SWOC, Steel Flash; Steel Blast, 1939; 9 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 9. April-August, 1939.
  - Correspondence, 1940; 10 (Reel 9)
    Box 13: Folder 10.
  - Correspondence, 1941; 11 (Reel 9)
    Box 14: Folder 1.
  - Clippings, 1941; 12 (Reel 9)
    Box 14: Folder 2.
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1942; 13 (Reel 9)
    Box 14: Folder 3. January-September, 1942.
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1942; 14 (Reel 9)
    Box 14: Folder 4. October-December, 1942.
  - Clippings, 1942-1944; 15 (Reel 9)
    Box 14: Folder 5.
  - Steelworkers official papers, 1943; 16 (Reel 9)
    Box 14: Folder 6. January-November, 1943.
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1943; 17 (Reel 9)
    Box 15: Folder 1. November-December, 1943.
- 1944-1946 (Reel 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1944; 1 (Reel 10)
    Box 15: Folder 2.
  - Tool and Die, 1944-1945; 2 (Reel 10)
    Box 15: Folder 3. August 1944 - March 1945.
  - General, 1945; 3 (Reel 10)
    Box 15: Folder 4. January-June, 1945.
  - Post war planning, 1945; 4 (Reel 10)
    Box 15: Folder 5. January-March, 1945.
  - Clippings, 1945; 5 (Reel 10)
    Box 15: Folder 6. January- March, 1945.
  - Workers' education, 1945; 6 (Reel 10)
    Box 15: Folder 7. April 5, 1945.
  - General, 1945; 7 (Reel 10)
    Box 16: Folder 1. July-December, 1945.
  - Cleveland Regional War Labor Board, 1945; 8 (Reel 10)
    Box 16: Folder 2. December, 1945.
  - General, 1946; 9 (Reel 10)
    Box 16: Folder 3.
- Jan-Dec 1947 (Reel 11)
  - General, 1947; 1 (Reel 11)
    Box 16: Folder 4. January-March, 1947.
  - Negotiations, 1947; 2 (Reel 11)
    Box 16: Folder 5. January, 1947.
  - Germany: American Zone, 1947; 3 (Reel 11)
    Box 16: Folder 6. January-July, 1947.
  - General, 1947; 4 (Reel 11)
    Box 17: Folder 1. April-May, 1947.
  - General, 1947; 5 (Reel 11)
    Box 17: Folder 2. June-August, 1947.
  - Applications for World Federation of Trade Unions' (WFTU) positions, 1947; 6 (Reel 11)
    Box 17: Folder 3. May-October, 1947.
  - General, 1947; 7 (Reel 11)
    Box 17: Folder 4. September, 1947.
  - General, 1947; 8 (Reel 11)
    Box 17: Folder 5. October, 1947.
  - French-American Trade Union Committee, 1947; 9 (Reel 11)
    Box 17: Folder 6. September-November, 1947.
- Oct 1947 to Feb 1948 (Reel 12)
  - Palestine (Israel) delegation, 1947; 1 (Reel 12)
    Box 17: Folder 7. October-December, 1947.
  - General, 1947; 2 (Reel 12)
    Box 18: Folder 1. November, 1947.
  - General, 1947; 3 (Reel 12)
    Box 18: Folder 2. December, 1947.
  - Clippings, 1947-1948; 4 (Reel 12)
    Box 18: Folder 3.
  - General, 1948; 5 (Reel 12)
    Box 18: Folder 4.
  - General, 1948; 6 (Reel 12)
    Box 19: Folder 1. January 1-19, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 7 (Reel 12)
    Box 19: Folder 2. January 20-31, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 8 (Reel 12)
    Box 19: Folder 3. February, 1948.
- Mar 1948 to Aug 1948 (Reel 13)
  - General, 1948; 1 (Reel 13)
    Box 19: Folder 4. March 1-24, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 2 (Reel 13)
    Box 19: Folder 5. March 25 - April 30, 1948.
  - Travel notes, 1948; 3 (Reel 13)
    Box 20: Folder 1. May 1-29 (and scattered dates to Oct. 25), 1948.
  - General, 1948; 4 (Reel 13)
    Box 20: Folder 2. May 1948.
  - General, 1948; 5 (Reel 13)
    Box 20: Folder 3. June 1-28, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 6 (Reel 13)
    Box 20: Folder 4. June 28-July 8, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 7 (Reel 13)
    Box 20: Folder 5. July 9-31, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 8 (Reel 13)
    Box 20: Folder 6. August, 1948.
- Congress of Industrial Org., Sep 1948 to Jay Krane's Communications Dec 1948 (Reel 14)
  - CIO - Trade Union Congress (TUC) relationships, 1948; 1 (Reel 14)
    Box 21: Folder 1. September-December, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 2 (Reel 14)
    Box 21: Folder 2. September 1-15, 1948.
  - Meeting Exec. Bur., WFTU, 1948; 3 (Reel 14)
    Box 21: Folder 3. September 17-21, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 4 (Reel 14)
    Box 21: Folder 4. September 20-30, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 5 (Reel 14)
    Box 21: Folder 5. October 1-12, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 6 (Reel 14)
    Box 22: Folder 1. October 13-17, 1948.
  - General, 1948; 7 (Reel 14)
    Box 22: Folder 2. October 18-28, 1948.
  - Jay Krane's communications to Cope, 1948; 8 (Reel 14)
    Box 22: Folder 3. October 28-December 23, 1948.
- Nov 1948 to Jan 1949 (Reel 15)
  - General, 1948; 1 (Reel 15)
    Box 22: Folder 4. November, 1948
  - General, 1948; 2 (Reel 15)
    Box 22: Folder 5. December, 1948
  - Undated; clippings, 1948; 3 (Reel 15)
    Box 23: Folder 1. Undated; clippings
  - General, 1949; 4 (Reel 15)
    Box 23: Folder 2. January 1-16, 1949
  - General, 1949; 5 (Reel 15)
    Box 23: Folder 3. January 17-19, 1949
  - General, 1949; 6 (Reel 15)
    Box 23: Folder 4. January 19-31, 1949
- Feb 1949 to Jun 1949 (Reel 16)
  - General, 1949; 1 (Reel 16)
    Box 24: Folder 1. February 1-19, 1949
  - Travel notes by Mrs. Cope, 1949; 2 (Reel 16)
    Box 24: Folder 2. February 20-April 22, 1949
  - General, 1949; 3 (Reel 16)
    Box 24: Folder 3. February 20-28, 1949
  - General, 1949; 4 (Reel 16)
    Box 24: Folder 4. March 1-12, 1949
  - International Trade Secretariats (ITS) Conference, Bournemouth, England, 1949; 5 (Reel 16)
    Box 24: Folder 5. March 8-10, 1949
  - General, 1949; 6 (Reel 16)
    Box 24: Folder 6. March 13-19, 1949
  - General, 1949; 7 (Reel 16)
    Box 25: Folder 1. March 21-31, 1949
  - Round the world Town Meeting tour, 1949; 8 (Reel 16)
    Box 25: Folder 2. March 28-June 15, 1949
- Apr 1949 to Jul 1949 (Reel 17)
  - General, 1949; 1 (Reel 17)
    Box 25: Folder 3. April
  - General, 1949; 2 (Reel 17)
    Box 25: Folder 4. May 1-18, 1949
  - General, 1949; 3 (Reel 17)
    Box 25: Folder 5. May 19-31, 1949
  - General, 1949; 4 (Reel 17)
    Box 26: Folder 1. June 1-15, 1949
  - General, 1949; 5 (Reel 17)
    Box 26: Folder 2. June 16-30, 1949
  - Round the world Town Meeting tour, 1949; 6 (Reel 17)
    Box 26: Folder 3. June 15-July 25, 1949
- Jun 1949 to Sep 1949 (Reel 18)
  - Geneva Preparatory meeting, International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU), 1949; 1 (Reel 18)
    Box 26: Folder 4. June 25-26 Geneva Preparatory meeting, International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU)
  - General, 1949; 2 (Reel 18)
    Box 26: Folder 5. July (except 25th-29th), 1949
  - London meeting ICFTU Preparatory Committee, 1949; 3 (Reel 18)
    Box 27: Folder 1. July 25-29, 1949
  - Round the world Town Meeting tour, 1949; 4 (Reel 18)
    Box 27: Folder 2. July 27-October 18 Round the world Town Meeting tour
  - Ruhr analysis, 1949; 5 (Reel 18)
    Box 27: Folder 3. July 31-September 29, 1949
  - General, 1949; 6 (Reel 18)
    Box 27: Folder 4. August 1-11, 1949
  - General, 1949; 7 (Reel 18)
    Box 27: Folder 5. August 12-September 18, 1949
- Sep 1949 to Nov 1949 (Reel 19)
  - General, 1949; 1 (Reel 19)
    Box 28: Folder 1. September 9-16, 1949
  - General, 1949; 2 (Reel 19)
    Box 28: Folder 2. September 17-30, 1949
  - General, 1949; 3 (Reel 19)
    Box 28: Folder 3. October 1-20, 1949
  - General, 1949; 4 (Reel 19)
    Box 28: Folder 4. October 21-November 7, 1949
  - General, 1949; 5 (Reel 19)
    Box 28: Folder 5. November 8-19, 1949
  - International Metalworkers Federation (IMF) Central Committee meeting, 1949; 6 (Reel 19)
    Box 29: Folder 1. November 20-26, 1949
  - General, 1949; 7 (Reel 19)
    Box 29: Folder 2. November 24-28
- Nov 1949 to 1949, uncertain dates (Reel 20)
  - ICFTU London Congress, 1949; 1 (Reel 20)
    Box 29: Folder 3. November 28-December 9, 1949
  - General, 1949; 2 (Reel 20)
    Box 29: Folder 4. December 1-15, 1949
  - General, 1949; 3 (Reel 20)
    Box 30: Folder 1. December 16-31, 1949
  - General, 1949; 4 (Reel 20)
    Box 30: Folder 2. Uncertain dates
- Jan 1949 to Jan 1950 (Reel 21)
  - Clippings, 1949; 1 (Reel 21)
    Box 30: Folder 3. January-February, 1949
  - Clippings, 1949; 2 (Reel 21)
    Box 30: Folder 4. March-September, 1949
  - Clippings, 1949; 3 (Reel 21)
    Box 30: Folder 5. October-December, 1949
  - General, 1950; 4 (Reel 21)
    Box 31: Folder 1. January 1-16, 1950
  - General, 1950; 5 (Reel 21)
    Box 31: Folder 2. January 17-22, 1950
  - General, 1950; 6 (Reel 21)
    Box 31: Folder 3. January 23-31, 1950
- Jan 1950 to Mar 1950 (Reel 22)
  - Ruhr: International Trade Union Committee, 1950; 1 (Reel 22)
    Box 31: Folder 4. January-March, 1950
  - General, 1950; 2 (Reel 22)
    Box 32: Folder 1. February 1-15, 1950
  - Trade unions: Denmark, Norway, Sweden, 1950; 3 (Reel 22)
    Box 32: Folder 2. February 7-March 19, 1950
  - General, 1950; 4 (Reel 22)
    Box 32: Folder 3. February 17-28
  - General, 1950; 5 (Reel 22)
    Box 32: Folder 4. March 1-9, 1950
  - General, 1950; 6 (Reel 22)
    Box 32: Folder 5. March 10-18, 1950
  - ICFTU meetings at Brussels, 1950; 7 (Reel 22)
    Box 33: Folder 1. March 15-18, 1950
  - General, 1950; 8 (Reel 22)
    Box 33: Folder 2. March 19-31, 1950
- Apr 1950 to May 1950 (Reel 23)
  - General, 1950; 1 (Reel 23)
    Box 33: Folder 3. April 1-18, 1950
  - Third conference of European Recovery Program (ERP) trade union organizations, 1950; 2 (Reel 23)
    Box 33: Folder 4. April. 18-20, 1950
  - General, 1950; 3 (Reel 23)
    Box 34: Folder 1. April 19-30, 1950
  - General (except ICFTU Exec. Bd. Meeting 5/25-27), 1950; 4 (Reel 23)
    Box 34: Folder 2. May, 1950 (except ICFTU Exec. Bd. Meeting 5/25-27)
  - Travel notes by Mrs. Cope, 1950; 5 (Reel 23)
    Box 34: Folder 3. May 24-July 7, 1950
  - ICFTU Exec. Bd. Meeting, Brussels, 1950; 6 (Reel 23)
    Box 34: Folder 4. May 25-27, 1950
- Jun 1950 to Aug 1950 (Reel 24)
  - General, 1950; 1 (Reel 24)
    Box 34: Folder 5. June 1-20, 1950
  - General, 1950; 2 (Reel 24)
    Box 35: Folder 1. June 20-30, 1950
  - Schumann Plan report, 1950; 3 (Reel 24)
    Box 35: Folder 2. June 20-August 10, 1950
  - General, 1950; 4 (Reel 24)
    Box 35: Folder 3. July, 1950 (except IMF meeting 7/10-15)
  - IMF meeting, Stockholm, 1950; 5 (Reel 24)
    Box 35: Folder 4. July 10-15, 1950
  - General, 1950; 6 (Reel 24)
    Box 35: Folder 5. August, 1950
- Sep 1950 to Dec 1951 (Reel 25)
  - General, 1950; 1 (Reel 25)
    Box 36: Folder 1. September, 1950 (except ICFTU meeting 9/13-17)
  - ICFTU Emergency Committee meeting, Brussels, 1950; 2 (Reel 25)
    Box 36: Folder 2. September 13-15, 1950
  - General, 1950; 3 (Reel 25)
    Box 36: Folder 3. October 1-15, 1950
  - General, 1950; 4 (Reel 25)
    Box 36: Folder 4. October 16-31, 1950
  - General, 1950; 5 (Reel 25)
    Box 37: Folder 1. November-December, 1950
  - ICFTU Exec. Bd. Meeting, Brussels, 1950; 6 (Reel 25)
    Box 37: Folder 2. November 9-11, 1950
  - ICFTU circulars, 1950-1951; 7 (Reel 25)
    Box 37: Folder 3. November 29, 1950 - May 23, 1951
- 1950-1951 Press releases 1950-1951 Economic stabilization to Feb-Mar 1951 (Reel 26)
  - ICFTU press releases, 1950-1951; 1 (Reel 26)
    Box 37: Folder 4.December 1950-April 1951